What exactly were the people of ages past thinking as they selectively bred these ugly creatures?
数百年前の人々は
一体 何を考えて
これほど醜悪な生き物に
わざわざ品種改良を
施したのだろうか？
あのバカそっくり…
It’s just like that idiot.
もちろん
絶対的な権力を持つ女王に
Of course, very few species of mammals exhibit eusocial behavior like that of worker bees obeying an almighty queen.
ワーカーたちが従う
ミツバチのごとき
真社会性を持った哺乳類は
非常に限られる
同じように
If a mammalian species that lived in underground communities was what they were looking for,
穴居性で集団生活を送る
哺乳類がよいというのなら
then surely meerkats would have been less revolting candidates.
ミーアキャットの方が
ずっと見栄えもよくて
親しまれたのではないだろうか…
ともあれ
ハダカデバネズミの飼育は
In any case, raising naked molerats is now my responsibility, whether I like it or not.
いやおう無しに
私の担当となってしまったが
Well, I suppose it is not my main responsibility.
何も
これが本業というわけではない
私に与えられた本来の職務は
茅輪の郷にある
My true responsibility is the investigation and regulation of queerats at the Department of Exospecies Control
町立保健所の
異類管理課という部署で
バケネズミの実態調査と
管理を行うことだった
at the communal Health Care Center in the village of Hayring.
早季ちゃん
あっ！
You’ve got a visitor, Saki-chan!
お客さんだよ～
は～い すぐ行きます～
Okay, I’ll be right there!
237年の７月
In July of the year 237,
私は26歳になっていた
I turned 26.
Episode Seventeen
Footsteps of Destruction
Department of Exospecies Control
失礼します
Excuse me.
Department of Exospecies Control
あっ 覚…
Satoru.
アハッ…
He says you two used to be in the same class.
朝比奈君とは
同級生だったんだって？
えっ？ ええ… そうです
Y-Yes. That’s right.
２人で お昼でも行ってきたら？
Why don’t you two go out and have lunch?
いや 別に そんな…
あの 今日 伺ったのは
No, we—
Actually, I’m here on business today.
職務上のことですので
Oh? Really?
うん？ そう？
I’ll head out for some lunch, then.
じゃあ 僕が先に行ってくるよ
えっ？
エヘッ…
課長さん 勝手に気を回して…
Your boss has an eager imagination.
それで？
Well?
何のご用でございましょうか？
How may I help you?
あっ ああ… バケネズミのことで
Uh, it’s about the queerats.
ちょっと
聞きたかったん… だけ… ど…
I have some… questions…
でしょうね
ここは異類管理課ですから… で？
Figures.
This is the Department of Exospecies Control, after all.
Well?
あっ… あのさ
Say, is there a colony at war somewhere right now?
今 戦争をしてるコロニーって
どこか あるのかな？
どこにも ないはずだけど…
There shouldn’t be.
本当？
Are you sure?
どっか 小競り合いをしてるとか？
No skirmishes, nothing?
Application for Intercolonial War
バケネズミは
The queerats are obligated to hand in this application before they can go to war.
戦争前には これの提出が
義務づけられているの
怠った場合 最悪 コロニーが
消滅させられることもあるから
They risk annihilation of their colony as punishment if they don’t submit it, so it’s unthinkable that they wouldn’t.
出さないなんて考えられないわ
｢コロニー間の
戦争行為等許可申請書｣
“Application for Intercolonial War.”
ふ～ん 奇襲をかけようと思っても
Do they have to fill this out even if they want to launch a surprise attack?
前もって こんなの書かされんのか
別に 相手に情報が
漏れるわけじゃないもの
It’s not like we’d leak the information to their enemy.
｢コロニー間統廃合届｣と
｢幼獣等管理移転申請書｣か
“Intercolonial Reorganization Notice.”
“Whelp Transfer Application.”
I see.
なるほどね…
だから どのコロニーでも
I guess that’s why they need a
literate member in every colony.
言葉の堪能なやつが
必要になるのか
ねえ…
うん？
Hey.
バカバカしいって思ってる？
えっ？
Ridiculous, isn’t it?
This must be so dumb to you.
くだらないって思うでしょ？
お役所仕事って
結局 形式ばかりなのよ…
All this pencil-pushing isn’t doing anything.
What you do is different and actually helps the village.
覚みたいに 本当の意味で
町の発展に役立つ仕事とは
違うもの…
That’s a bit harsh.
ああ… いや そんなことは…
ただ…
It’s just… How do I put this?
何というか… 文言が特殊だよな
The choice of words is peculiar.
Why do we call the queerats “exospecies”?
なんで バケネズミのことを
｢異類｣って言いかえるのかな？
｢バケネズミ管理課｣じゃ
あんまりだからじゃない？
Don’t you think “Department of
Queerat Control” has a weird ring to it?
フッ… そりゃそうだな
You have a point.
So, why would you think the queerats are waging war?
それより どうして バケネズミが
戦争してるかなんて思ったの？
ウチでは よく
We often let the queerats gather samples for us.
バケネズミに
試料の収集をやらすんだ
妙法農場では
You’re using the Spider Wasp colony at the Lotus Farm, right?
鼈甲蜂コロニーを
使ってるんだっけ？
うん 最近 櫟林の郷で
Yeah.
They’ve been gathering slime molds around Oakgrove for us lately.
粘菌の採集をやらせていたんだ
It seems they were attacked yesterday morning.
それが 昨日の朝
攻撃を受けたみたいなんだ…
攻撃？
Attacked?
They said they were fired upon suddenly.
いきなり 矢を放ってきたらしい
Maybe some hunters made a mistake?
狩りをしてて
間違えたんじゃない？
いや 物陰に潜んで
狙い打ちしてきたんだ
No, the attackers hid themselves and ambushed them.
故意にやってる
It was on purpose.
I wonder if they knew they were attacking the Spider Wasps.
向こうは 鼈甲蜂ってことも
分かってたのかしら？
どうして？
Why?
I’m surprised the Spider Wasps were attacked.
鼈甲蜂ってのが引っ掛かるのよ
They’re close allies of the Giant Hornets.
大雀蜂の直系だもん
奇狼丸に宣戦布告したのと
同じことになるわ…
It’s like sending a declaration of war to Kiroumaru.
だとすると やっぱ外来種かな？
So we should suspect a foreign species, shouldn’t we?
ここしばらく 現れてないわ
We haven’t seen any around here in a long time.
そっか…
I see.
I was hoping someone in your department would know.
ここに来れば
分かると思ったんだけどな
ねえ 鼈甲蜂は
妙法農場に被害を訴えてきたの？
Hey, did the Spider Wasps come to the
Lotus Farm to complain about the attack?
いや ウチの職員が たまたま森で
No, one of our men ran into the Spider Wasps in the forest.
その鼈甲蜂の連中に会ったんだ
They asked for help so he searched the area with them, but to no avail.
助けを求めてきたんで
すぐに付近を捜したけど
その時は もう…
ふ～ん
This isn’t something we can ignore.
こんな事態を放っておいたら
大問題だろ？
It’s interfering with the samples I need collected, and above all it doesn’t respect our authority.
試料収集にも差し支えるし
何より 人間がなめられるよ
分かった 大至急 調べてみるわ
All right.
We’ll investigate the matter as soon as possible.
攻撃をしたコロニーが分かれば
Once we identify the culprits’ colony,
we’ll need to take disciplinary action.
何らかの懲罰が
必要になると思うし
最悪 有害鳥獣対策課の出番かもね
In the worst case, we’ll have to involve the Department of Pest Control.
ぷっ
何？
What?
いや…
早季が１人で仕切ってるから
Nothing, you just seemed like the real department chief around here with the way you talked.
ここの課長みたいだなって…
この時の私の中には
Satoru and I fell out over something petty a while back,
どこかのバカな
コロニーのおかげで
つまらないことで
けんかをしていた覚と
so I was happy that some stupid colony gave us the chance to make up.
仲直りする きっかけができたと
喜ぶ気持ちさえあった…
しかし 町で 最もバケネズミに
警戒心を持っていた私ですら
However, despite being the person in the village most wary of the queerats,
これが どんなに
恐ろしい事件の幕開けなのか
I could not even begin to imagine what terrible events this would foreshadow.
想像だにしていなかった…
優先議題がありますので
We have a priority matter to discuss, so we will be skipping the reports from each department.
各課の定例報告は省略します
職能会議代表の日野光風氏
Sir Hino Koufuu of the Occupations Council.
安全保障会議顧問の鏑木肆星氏
Sir Kaburagi Shisei, consultant to the Security Council.
And lastly, Lady Asahina Tomiko, head of the Ethics Committee.
そして 倫理委員会議長の
朝比奈 富子氏にも
Welcome.
ご出席いただきます
１週間前に 鼈甲蜂コロニーの
One week ago, six exospecies from the Spider Wasp colony were attacked by an unknown party.
Peace and Cooperation
異類６匹が正体不明の相手から
攻撃を受けるという事件が
ありました
うち ２匹は毒矢を受けて
絶命しております
Two have perished from poison arrows.
関東近郊にある異類コロニーは
The various exospecies colonies in the wider
Kanto area can be grouped into two factions.
２つのグループによって
集約化が進み
現在は
ほぼ均衡状態に達しています
Presently their power is in balance.
第１のグループが
大雀蜂系です
The first group consists of all colonies under the Giant Hornets.
Their own forces number roughly a hundred thousand,
兵力は約10万匹
傘下の有力コロニーは
and thirteen more colonies such as the Spider Wasps are affiliated with them.
鼈甲蜂をはじめ 13コロニーあり
これらを合算した総兵力は
50万匹です
Their total forces are five hundred thousand warriors.
They have proven extremely loyal to humans
and are entrusted with important physical labor.
極めて人間に忠実で
貴重な労働力の
担い手でもあります
質問しても かまいませんか？
May I ask a question?
どうぞ
Please.
バケネズミ… 異類ですか…
The queerats… “Exospecies,” you called them?
これらのコロニーは
What sort of bond holds their colonies together?
どういう つながりで
結びついているんですか？
グループは 一枚岩と考えても
いいんでしょうか？
Can their groups be considered monolithic?
大雀蜂系は
各コロニーごとに女王を頂き
Each colony in the Giant Hornet faction serves their own queen,
封建的な主従関係で
結ばれています
and they have established a feudal system of masters and servants.
また 互いに血縁を強めており
Additionally they go to some lengths to
strengthen blood ties between colonies.
グループ内の裏切りは
まず 考えられません
Treason is therefore highly unlikely.
分かりました 続けてください
I see. Please continue.
うっ…
第２グループが塩屋虻系です
The others can be grouped under the Robber Fly colony.
Their own forces amount to roughly fifty-five thousand,
兵力は 約５万5,000匹
これに８つのコロニーが加わり
and eight more colonies are associated with them.
総兵力は 30万匹程度と思われます
Their collected forces are believed to number three hundred thousand.
They, too, show dutiful allegiance to humans
こちらも人間に対しては
恭順な姿勢を見せており
かねてから 大雀蜂系が
独占する人間の仕事を
and have suggested for some time now that they be allowed to share the work given solely to the Giant Hornets.
分担したいと申し入れております
塩屋虻系では コロニー間の融合が
比較にならないほど進んでいます
The integration of these colonies is far more advanced.
どういうことですか？
What do you mean?
They have all overthrown the rule of their queens by means of revolution,
彼らは革命によって
女王の支配を覆しており
意志決定は 選挙によって選ばれた
代議員が行います
and their decision-making is carried out by elected representatives.
女王の職務は 完全に
生殖だけに限定されています
The duties of their queens have been reduced to reproduction.
One by one colonies have gravitated to either of the
two groups, leaving practically no independent ones.
この２グループによる
集約化が進んだ結果
いずれにも くみしない
独立系のコロニーは
ほとんど残っていません
So essentially, there is a high chance that the Spider Wasps were attacked by members of the Robber Fly group?
すると 鼈甲蜂コロニーに
攻撃を加えたのは
塩谷虻系コロニーの
可能性が高いということですか？
現場の遺留物を
慎重に鑑定した結果
On careful analysis of the evidence at the scene,
the Goat Moth colony was identified as the attacker.
襲撃したのは木蠹蛾コロニーと
判明いたしました
The Goat Moths?
木蠹蛾？
The Goat Moths have repeatedly declared their neutrality for over a decade now.
木蠹蛾コロニーは十数年前から
中立を宣言しております
However, for all intents and purposes, they can be considered closely allied with the Robber Fly colony.
ですが 現状では
極めて 塩屋虻系に近いと
認識しております
なるほど そういう話ですか！
Okay! I got this!
場合によっては
So basically, the destruction of
only one colony might not suffice!
１コロニーの消滅では
終わらんということだ
もし 塩屋虻系
全体が関与していたとすれば
This could be taken as a direct opposition to human rule if all the Robber Fly colonies were involved in this conspiracy.
これは人間に対する
反逆といってもいい
ここいら辺におる
バケネズミの半数を
We might have to stamp out half the queerats around here!
駆除することになるやもしれんな
ハッハハ…
いや… そこまでは まだ…
Well, it’s still too early to say…
そ… それでは
I-I would like to summon the two exospecies
representatives awaiting further instructions.
待機させてある異類の代表を
呼びたいと思います
We have the supreme commander of the Giant Hornet colony, Kiroumaru,
大雀蜂コロニーの
主席司令官である奇狼丸と
and the representative of the Robber Fly colony, Yakomaru.
塩谷虻コロニーの代表 野狐丸です
Which would you like to question first?
どちらから
聴取いたしましょうか？
両方いっぺんに入れたら
どうかしら？
Both at once, I suggest.
えっ？
もし 話が食い違うようなら
If their stories do not match up, they can be made to confront each other to see who’s telling the truth.
直接 対決させた方が
白黒つけやすいでしょ？
Peace and Cooperation
え～ それでは まず奇狼丸に聞く
Well then, I shall address you first, Kiroumaru.
鼈甲蜂コロニーの兵士が
襲われた事件は知っているね？
I believe you are aware that Spider Wasp soldiers have been attacked.
はい
Yes.
Do you hold anyone guilty?
相手の目星はついているのか？
生き残った兵士から
事情聴取した結果
Based on what the survivors have relayed to me,
直接 手を下したのは
木蠹蛾コロニーだと分かりました
the party immediately responsible for the attack is the Goat Moth colony.
あ～ つまり 指令を下したものが
別にいたということか？
So it is your suspicion that they received an order?
はい
Yes.
The Goat Moth colony is merely part of the Robber Flies now.
木蠹蛾コロニーは
塩屋虻と 一体です
したがって 塩屋虻の命を
受けたものと思われます
We can assume the former received orders from the latter.
では 野狐丸に聞こう
Let us hear Yakomaru then.
今の奇狼丸の発言は本当か？
Is Kiroumaru’s accusation true?
とんでもございません！
Absolutely not!
By the deities of Heaven and Earth,
I swear that no such order was issued.
天地神明に誓いまして そのような
指令は出しておりません！
しかし 木蠹蛾コロニーは
お前の傘下にある
But is the Goat Moth colony not affiliated with you?
というより
その 一部ではないのか？
Or, rather, under your rule?
確かに 私どもは
木蠹蛾コロニーと接近し
Not quite.
We have approached the Goat Moths and labored to join forces.
合流を働きかけてきました
However, our efforts have yet to bear fruit.
しかし いまだに
実現しておりません
彼らは旧弊な思考に
とらわれており
They still cling to the old way of thinking and
cannot bear to leave monarchical rule behind.
女王を頂く体制から
どうしても決別できないからです
もうひとつ 木蠹蛾は
大雀蜂コロニーから
Moreover, the Giant Hornets have had their eyes set on the Goat Moths for a long time now.
虎視たんたんと狙われている
という事情もございます
Threatened with immediate
repercussions should they ally with us,
私どもと合流すれば
ただちに攻撃されると
どう喝されていたため
どうにも動けなかったはずです
it appears to me their options were awfully limited.
今の話は真実なのか？
Is this true?
まったくもって笑止千万！
It is completely absurd!
It is the nonsense of one who masks lies with lies!
ウソをウソで塗り固めた詭弁
たわ言です！
どうか この二枚舌の語る言葉に
I beg you not to trust the words of this treacherous snake.
惑わされませぬよう
お願い致します
As for his first claim, I have been informed that the queen of the Goat Moths is already a captive.
第１の点で言えば
木蠹蛾コロニーの女王は
すでに幽閉状態にあると
聞き及びます
第２の点もしかり
As for the second, I must make it clear we have never threatened them in any way.
私どもが脅したなどという事実は
一切ございません
野狐丸
Yakomaru!
I must profess my surprise.
いや はや… 驚きました…
一体どこから
What could be the source of such prattle?
そのようなデタラメを
吹き込まれましたのやら…
The queen of the Goat Moths is in
good health and ruling over her colony,
木蠹蛾コロニーの女王は
今もご健在で
コロニーに君臨なさっております
政務に関しましては
有能な摂政であるクイーチーに
although she entrusts political matters to her very capable regent, Queachy.
お任せになっているようですが…
What gall you have to lie in front of gods!
神の御前で よくも
それだけ ウソが出てくるものだ！
お前の その汚れた口を
引き裂いてやろうか！
Perhaps I should rip your filthy mouth open!
奇狼丸 許された時以外
発言してはならん
Kiroumaru, you may not speak unless addressed.
野狐丸といったかしら？
Your name was Yakomaru, I believe?
木蠹蛾コロニーの女王が健在で
I believe you said the Goat Moth queen is in good health but leaves the affairs of government to a regent?
しかし 政務は摂政が代行している
と言いましたね？
ははっ 間違いございません
Yes, that is correct.
う～ん でも そこまで
木蠹蛾の内情に詳しいのなら
But if you are that familiar with their colony’s inner workings,
少なくともお前のコロニーの方が
doesn’t it imply that your own colony has a more
intimate relationship with them than Kiroumaru’s?
奇狼丸より密接な関係にあるのは
事実じゃないの？
は… あの… それは…
Uh, you see…
その 先ほど申し上げました通り
As I explained earlier, we put considerable effort into building a good relationship with them,
関係を構築する努力を
続けてまいりましたので
内部事情にも詳しく…
so I am somewhat familiar with their inner workings.
ただ 親しいといいましても
神のご意志に背くような攻撃を
But however close we may be, it is unthinkable that we would order them to defy the will of the gods,
私どもが命じるなど 沙汰の限り
そのようなことをすれば神罰が
下るのは明白ではありませんか
considering that divine punishment would quickly befall us.
では 木蠹蛾コロニーが
単独でやったと言うの？
So you are suggesting the Goat Moths acted rashly and on their own?
That does not make much sense to me either.
お前の話だと
それもまた おかしな話になるけど
そのことにつきましては 私なりに
考えていることがございます
I have my own theories regarding that.
申し述べさせて頂いても
よろしゅうございましょうか？
May I elaborate?
いいわ 言ってみなさい
Certainly. Go on.
はい
たとえ 私どもが命じたにせよ
Gladly.
For the sake of argument, let us assume we gave the Goat Moths the order or they made a hasty decision.
木蠹蛾の跳ね上がりが
やったにせよ
神のお許しもなく 他のコロニーを
攻撃するというのは
Either way, attacking another colony
without divine permission is simply insane.
血迷ったという以外
全く説明がつきません
But what if this was orchestrated by the Spider Wasps?
しかしです これがもし
鼈甲蜂コロニーによる
自作自演だったとすれば
いかがでございましょう？
木蠹蛾コロニーの使っている
矢や弓 かっちゅうなどは
It would not be difficult for them to obtain the arrows, bows and armor of the Goat Moths.
その気になれば
いくらでも入手可能です
その上で 二手に分かれて
一芝居打ち
Perhaps they split into two groups, staged an attack, and played the victim?
被害者を
装ったのではないでしょうか？
私どもと
大雀蜂グループとは
My alliance and the Giant Hornet group are well balanced at present,
勢力が きっ抗しておりますので
真正面からぶつかれば 双方が
多大の損害を被ることでしょう
so a direct confrontation would result in grievous losses for both sides.
口にするのも畏れ多いことですが
I am afraid to even suggest this,
but perhaps the Giant Hornets themselves
may have wanted to rely on divine assistance
大雀蜂どもは
神様をたばかることで
あわよくば 自分たちは無傷のまま
私どもを
滅そうとしたのではないかと…
to destroy us without having to expose themselves to danger.
しかし 鼈甲蜂コロニーでは２匹が
死亡しているではないか？
But didn’t the Spider Wasps lose two workers in the attack?
I assume the loss of a few lives amounts to nothing for them.
おそらく 彼らにとって
数匹の犠牲など
ものの数ではないのでしょう
In this they are fundamentally different from us.
この点が私どもと
根本的に違うところでございます
私どもは民主主義を
基本理念とするコロニーであり
Our colonies have embraced democracy, and every individual holds equal rights
一匹一匹が平等な権利を持つ
and is considered an irreplaceable existence in the universe.
この宇宙にかけがえのない存在と
考えておりますが
女王のみを絶対とする
古い体制では
The old system considers only the queen integral, and her soldiers are merely pawns.
兵士など しょせんは作戦の駒
They are all expendable.
消耗品でしかないのです！
Do you think what Yakomaru says holds water?
この者… 野狐丸の言うことは
真実の可能性はあるのかしら？
Well, common sense would dictate otherwise,
but his words cannot be immediately dismissed.
はい それは
常識では考えにくいことですが
絶対にないかと言われると
そうとも申し上げられません
さすがに全部 謀略であったという
可能性までは
I must admit we did not consider the possibility of a charade.
検討しておりませんでしたので…
Peace and Cooperation
In the end, the meeting was adjourned without a decision.
結局 この日は結論が出ないまま
散会となった
１時間のうちに
敵をせん滅してごらんにいれます
Within the hour you shall witness the annihilation of our enemies.
May the fortunes of war favor you.
ご武運をお祈りします
You command the main force of the Giant Hornet army numbering a hundred thousand.
こちら側の
大雀蜂軍本隊が10万匹
対する相手側が
連合軍で14万匹ですね
You face allied forces numbering a hundred and forty thousand.
どうして連合軍に
Why is the Robber Fly colony’s main army not included in the allied forces?
塩屋虻コロニーの本隊は
いないんでしょうか？
That is something you should ask that silver-tongued coward.
それはあの口が達者な臆病者に
お聞きになった方が
よろしいかと思います
まあ 察するに 数が多くとも
I suspect they dare not face our strength directly even with superior numbers.
我が手勢と いきなり
相まみえる勇気がないのでしょう
Very well.
分かりました
それでは存分に戦ってください
Please fight as you desire.
We shall.
心得ました
Watanabe-san!
渡辺さん
もう少し下がった方がいいですよ
You should step back a little.
Oh, Inui-san!
乾さん
あの盾は
古代文明の戦国時代に考案された
Their shields look just like the bamboo ones used during the Warring States period of the ancient civilization.
｢竹束｣というものに似ています
頭がいいとは
思ってはいましたが…
I knew they were smart, but…
だが あれだけのものを全て
自力で考えだしたとは どうにも…
I find it very unlikely that those are all the product of their own ingenuity.
どういうことですか？
What do you mean?
I’m convinced they have some source of knowledge.
私には やつらがどこからか
何らかの知識を得てるとしか
思えないんですよ
すごい
Amazing…
たまに やつらの知恵が
怖くなることがありますよ
Every now and then their intelligence frightens me.
やつらが 私たち鳥獣保護官を
Do you know what they call us from the
Department of Pest Control amongst themselves?
陰で何と言ってるか
ご存知ですか？
いえ
No.
While ordinary humans are “gods,” we are “gods of death.”
普通の人間は神様なのに
私たちは死神ですよ
まあ しょうがないですがね
Not all that surprising, I suppose.
しかし
色んなコロニーを見てきましたが
At any rate, I’ve seen a number of colonies myself,
こういう戦になるとまず
so I can confidently say that none can stand
against the Giant Hornets in such confrontations.
大雀蜂軍に かなうものは
いないでしょうね
どうしてですか？
Why?
ここだけの話ですがね
実はやつらは合戦の前に
Don’t tell anyone, okay?
They take a certain drug before each battle.
ある種の薬物を
与えられているんです
A drug? You mean, narcotics?
薬物って… 麻薬ですか？
Something like that, at least.
…の ようなものでしょうね
I don’t know what it is exactly,
詳しいことは分からないのですが
どうやらそれを飲むと
but it seems that when they take it, their sense of duty is strengthened while their fear is suppressed.
使命感が高まる反面
一切の恐怖を感じなくなり
その結果として
攻撃性は極限まで高進し
As a result, they become extremely aggressive and the ultimate soldier is born.
無敵の兵士ができあがる
と いうわけです
That’s how it goes.
イヤ！ イー！
ウワー
ウェーア！
私としたことがお約束を
たがえてしまい
I am deeply ashamed I could not do as promised.
恥じ入るばかりです
It took more than an hour to crush this conglomerate of weaklings.
これしきの敵を捻りつぶすのに
１時間以上も
かかってしまいました
I’m back!
ただいま
お疲れさまです
Good evening!
そっちはどうだった？
How did it go for you?
大雀蜂軍の圧勝でした
The Giant Hornets won an overwhelming victory.
ふぅ… そうか
I see…
まあ 奇狼丸が指揮する本隊なら
当然かな
Well, I can’t say I’m surprised, since it
happened under Kiroumaru’s command.
課長の方はいかがでした？
What can you report, Chief?
Nobody quite foresaw it, really.
うん ちょっと…
予想外の結果でね
と いうことは
木蠹蛾が勝ったんですか？
Are you saying…
that the Goat Moths won?
In a sense.
と 言っていいのかなあ
寝返ったんだよ
鼈甲蜂コロニーが
The Spider Wasps changed sides.
Surprising, isn’t it?
驚くだろう？ いきなり鼈甲蜂軍が
戦線を離脱したから
The Spider Wasps left the battlefront without warning,
応援に来ていた他の軍は
ぼう然自失といった有り様でね
so the others that came to support them were thrown into disarray.
ほとんど何の攻防もなく
木蠹蛾軍の勝利が決まったんだよ
The Goat Moths won quite easily.
Wait a moment.
ちょっと待ってください
そもそもの発端は
Didn’t this all start when the Goat Moths attacked the Spider Wasps?
鼈甲蜂が木蠹蛾に
攻撃された事ですよね？
その当事者が寝返るなんて…
Why would they join their mortal enemies?
複雑怪奇だよな
Isn’t it an intriguing mystery?
そういえば
結局 鼈甲蜂コロニーは
Which reminds me, the Spider Wasps
never filed a complaint about the attack.
ここに被害届けを
出してないんです
何か 関係があるんですかね？
I wonder if that’s related.
Now, with one victory and one loss we’re back to where we started.
これで１勝１敗で
振り出しに戻ったんですね
それはどうかな？
I’m not so sure about that.
やっぱり実戦で大勝した
大雀蜂軍の優位は
The Giant Hornets did win an actual battle, so I’d say they’re still the superior side…
動かないんじゃないかなぁ
大雀蜂軍が全滅した
The Giant Hornet army was annihilated.
Nani mo iranai
何もいらない
I need nothing else
Anata ga ireba ii
あなたがいればいい
When you are by my side
Sotto yokogao iki wo korosu
そっと横顔 息を殺す
I look at you in profile and hold my breath
Mabataki sureba kieteshimaisou de
まばたきすれば消えてしまいそうで
I'm afraid it might vanish like an illusion if I blink now
Mitsumesasete suki da yo
凝視めさせて好きだよ
Let me look at you, I love you
Ah kigi ga furue furidashita yuki
ああ 木々が震え 降り出した雪
The trees shake in the wind and snow gathers on the ground
Ashiato futatsu shiroku
足跡 ふたつ 白く
Two lines of white footprints show
Toki yo tsumore
時よ 積もれ
Snowflakes of time, gather
Kami ni mune ni futari dake no yume ni
髪に 胸に ふたりだけの夢に
In our hair, our hearts, our dream
Sakenai hana no
咲けない花の
This flower cannot bloom
Tane wa yuki ni dakare
種は雪に抱かれ
And the snow embraces its seeds
Yorisou no
寄り添うの
As they huddle together
Shizuka ni wasureraretai
静かに忘れられたい
Quietly they wish to be able to forget
I’m sure of it.
気のせいなんかじゃないの
いたの
She was there.
What about the ones who left the town a long time ago?
過去に町から出て行った人間は
どうでしょうか？
Those two have nothing to do with it.
あの２人は無関係です
早季は真理亜たちに会えた？
Saki, were you able to see Maria and Mamoru?
Yeah.